Guide to the Andrew Schultz Schultz, Jr. papers, 1932-1991
Schultz, Andrew Schultz, Jr. papers, 1932-1991
- Series XII. Engineering College: Reports, Proposals, Rosters, Photographs (Boxes 8, 11, 13, 19, 20, 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 35)
  - R. J. Pfeifer, talk at George Washington University 1956 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Western Electric Co. M.D.I.s, Sept. 1, 1952 1952 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Project Outline #1; Case No. ER 15006-1, March 1, 1960 1960 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Housekeeping, Maintenance, and Construction Program - Burlington Shop, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Western Electric Co. Proposed Conveyer Installation, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Western Electric Co. Article for Fortune Magazine, Dec. 1959 1959 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - The Scholarship Study; Preliminary Report, Feb. 1959 1959 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Engineering Effectiveness Study Advisory Committee; Meeting #5, May 4-5, 1960 1960 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Research Info on Engineering Employees, Feb. 1960 1960 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Handwritten Notes on Western Electric Co., parts 1-2 1960 (Box 19, Folder 12-13)
  - Western Electric Cost Accounting System, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Presentation - Research on Western Electric Co. (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Leaders Guide, Meeting the Engineering Challenge, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Proposal, Manufacturing Engineering Study 1961 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Western Electric Co. Research - Vu-Graphs (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Western Electric Co. Continuing Education Brochures 1982 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Summer Education Programs 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Dartmouth College, Projected Financial Impact of Year-Round Operation & Co-Education, Nov. 1971 1971 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Summer Session Operation Information 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Report of the Advisory Committee on Financial Planning, Sept. 1972 1972 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Office of the Dean, Dept. of Student Housing Info, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Draft of Cornell's Year Round Operation Proposal, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Year Round Operation Data 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Year-round operation reports 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Office of the President Memorandum, Jan. 15, 1975 1975 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Report of Priorities Study to President Corson, June 27, 1975 1975 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Paperwork for Academic Mission (Drafts) (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - ILR Support Staff Ratios, Mar. 1975 1975 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Responsibility Center Analysis, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Computing Services, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Budget Info. for Clerical and Technical Support, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Budget Info. General Expenses, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Engineering Non-Faculty Recoveries, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Cornell in the Seventies: Background Info. and Studies, May 1973 1973 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Trustee Report on Capital Financing, Jan. 1975 1975 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Task Force Report, May 15, 1975 1975 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - PIMS Business Strategy 1977-1979 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Conway, R.W. and Schultz, A. "The Manufacturing Progress Function" [1958] (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - The Manufacturing Progress Function, Misc. Papers 1969-1973 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - The Manufacturing Progress Function Manuscript 1954 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Handwritten Notes and Drawings, Operation Andy Appentices B, C, D Pre-1959 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Manufacturing Progress Function 1959 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Hammer, Kenneth Frederick, M.S. Thesis 1954 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Hand-Drawn Charts and Graphs, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Learning Curve Misc. Notes (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Wanvig, Thomas W. - Study of Manufacturing Progress Function Related to Ribbon Machine Operation, May 1957 1957 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - The Industrial Impact of Computing Systems, July 1961 1961 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Methods Time Measurement (MTM) Research Studies [Association Reports] 1966-1969 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Manufacturying cost reduction through the curve of natural productivity increase 1964 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Johnson, Ellis A. - Application of Operations Research to Industry (speech), 1953 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Conway, Richard W. - Study of Manufacturing Progress Function for Electronics Industry, Oct. 1954 1954 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Summary Report on Manufacturing Progress Function for Plant #1; Part 1, Aug. 1955 1955 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Summary Report on Manufacturing Progress Function for Plant #1; Part 2, Aug. 1955 1955 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Conway, A.W.; Schultz, A., Jr. - The Manufacturing Progress Function 1959 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Report of Manufacturing Progress Function Study 1954 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - "Fields open to the engineer," A. Schultz, Jr.; The Cornell Engineer, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Industrial Engineering Seminars, 1962 (Box 30)
  - Industrial Engineering Seminars, 1961 (Box 30)
  - Trustee Acknowledgments - Seminars, 1962 (Box 30)
  - Seminar Inquiries, 1963 (Box 30)
  - Misc. Photos, IE Seminars, and 5th-Year Projects (Box 30)
  - IE Seminars, June 1956 1956 (Box 30)
  - IE Seminars, June 1957 1957 (Box 30)
  - IE Seminars, June 1958 1958 (Box 30)
  - IE Seminars, 1959-1962 (Box 30)
  - Seminar Coffee Fund, 1957-1958 (Box 30)
  - Seminar Coffee Fund, 1956-57 (Box 30)
  - Seminar Payroll (Box 30)
  - Engineering Cornell Quarterly, 1966 (Box 30)
  - Job Placement Reports, 1972 (Box 30)
  - Job Placement Reports, 1964 (Box 30)
  - Job Placement Reports, 1964-1969 (Box 30)
  - Job Placement Reports, 1965-66 (Box 30)
  - IE Seminars, 1959 (Box 30)
  - "IE & Administration at Cornell," 1951-1952 (Box 30)
  - International Management Society (IMS) Talk, Dec. 1954 (Box 30)
  - IBM Talk, 1956 (Box 30)
  - ASQC - Boston, 1958 (Box 30)
  - ASQC - Boston, 1958 (cont.) (Box 30)
  - Paper - "The Next Big Decision" (Box 30)
  - Operations Research Handbook, 1959 (Box 30)
  - AIIE - Boston, 1960 (Box 30)
  - ASEE / AIEE Symposium - Detroit, 1959 (Box 30)
  - Reports: Industrial Engineering at Cornell, 1963 (Box 31)
  - Book: Lehrer, Robert. The Management of Improvement: Concepts, Organization, Strategy (Box 31)
  - Book: Listen to Leaders in Engineering (Box 31)
  - Leaders in Engineering, 1963 (Box 31)
  - Georgia Tech, 1963 (Box 31)
  - ICP Management Research, 1963 (Box 31)
  - Humanistic-Social Research Project of the ASEE, 1968 (Box 31)
  - ILR Meeting, 1964 (Box 31)
  - IE Standardization Meeting, 1963 (Box 31)
  - Cornell Engineering - Graduate School, 1963 (Box 31)
  - Cornell Centennial Talk - Pittsburgh, 1963 (Box 31)
  - Carnegie Tech Conference - Pittsburgh, 1965 (Box 31)
  - Syracuse U. Talk, 1965 (Box 31)
  - Cornell Talk - "Trends in Engineering Education," 1965 (Box 31)
  - Cornell Society of Engineers Newsletter, 1965 (Box 31)
  - Engineering Management Conference, 1966 (Box 31)
  - Information Systems Engineering Talk - Western Electric Co. Inc., 1966 (Box 31)
  - Mechanical Engineering Talk - Dublin, Ireland, 1966 (Box 31)
  - Mechanical Engineering Talk - Dublin, Ireland, 1966 (cont.) (Box 31)
  - Mechanical Engineering Talk - Dublin, Ireland, 1966 (cont.) (Box 31)
  - ASEE Meeting - Washington State U., 1966 (Box 31)
  - Equilibrium in Engineering Education Meeting, 1968 (Box 31)
  - OR Society of America - Symposium on Health, 1969 (Box 31)
  - ASME, 1970 (Box 31)
  - Cornell Society of Engineers Statements, 1971 (Box 31)
  - Cornell Convocation, 1971 (Box 31)
  - New Engineer Magazine, 1971 (Box 31)
  - University of Singapore Faculty of Engineering Conference, 1971 (Box 31)
  - University of Singapore Faculty of Engineering Conference, 1971 (cont.) (Box 31)
  - Panel Session on Accreditation ECPD, 1969 (Box 31)
  - ASEE - Industry-Engineering Educaiton Series, 1970 (Box 31)
  - Statement to Alumni, 1970 (Box 31)
  - Newspaper Articles (Box 32)
  - Various Engineering Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 32)
  - Various Engineering Reports, 1969 (Box 32)
  - Various Engineering Reports, 1972 (Box 32)
  - Singapore Pamphlets (Box 32)
  - Engineering Pamphlets (Box 32)
  - Engineering Pamphlets, 1969-70 (Box 32)
  - Basic Engineering - Education for the Professions (Box 32)
  - Comments on the Cranch Report, 1973 (Box 32)
  - Engineering: Cornell Quarterly; Engineering Education, 1978-1979 (Box 32)
  - Olmsted Project: Liberal Studies for the Engineer - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 32)
  - Olmsted Project: Liberal Studies for the Engineer - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 32)
  - ASEE - Liberal Learning for the Engineer, 1968 (Box 32)
  - Olmsted Project Report (Box 32)
  - Olmsted Project Report (Box 32)
  - Olmsted Project Report (Box 32)
  - Arts & Sciences (Box 32)
  - College Prep (Box 32)
  - Mechanical Engineering (Box 32)
  - Electrical Engineering (Box 32)
  - Engineering Physics (Box 32)
  - Chemical Engineering (Box 32)
  - College of Engineering Annual Reports, 1962-1963 (Box 32)
  - Annual Report, 1962-1963 (Box 32)
  - Annual Reports, 1960-1961 (Box 32)
  - Annual Report, 1956-1957 (Box 32)
  - Annual Report, 1959-1960 (Box 32)
  - Annual Report, 1958-1959 (Box 32)
  - Annual Report, 1957-1958 (Box 32)
  - Annual Report, 1956-1957 (Box 32)
  - Annual Report, 1955-1956 (Box 32)
  - Annual Report, 1956 (Box 32)
  - Annual Report, 1954 (Box 32)
  - Annual Report, 1953-1954 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report, 1952-1953 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report, 1951-1952 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report, 1949-1950, 1950-1951 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report, 1955-1956 (Box 33)
  - IE Administration Data (Box 33)
  - Annual Report, 1960-1961 (Box 33)
  - President's Report, 1970-1971 (Box 33)
  - Graduate Committee Report, 1956 (Box 33)
  - Annual Reports, 1962-1973 (Box 33)
  - Annual Reports, 1972-1974 (Box 33)
  - Annual Reports, 1970-1972 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report, 1976-1978 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report, 1980-1981 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report, 1971-1972 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report, 1974 (Box 33)
  - School of OR/IE Annual Report, 1971-1972 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1963-1964 (Box 33)
  - OR/IE: Annual Reports, 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - OR/IE: Annual Report, 1968-1969 (Box 33)
  - OR/IE: Annual Report, 1969-1970 (Box 33)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1968-1969 (Box 33)
  - Engineering Education Reports, 1965-1968 (Box 33)
  - Engineering College Memos, 1963-1964 (Box 34)
  - Report: Immediate Needs of the Engineering College, 1965 (Box 34)
  - College of Engineering Correspondence, 1962 (Box 34)
  - Curriculum Reorganization (Box 34)
  - Curriculum Reorganization, cont. (Box 34)
  - A Proposal for the College of Engineering - The Study Group for Mechanical Engineering, 1963 (Box 34)
  - EP-EE Aero Discussions (Box 34)
  - EE Study Group in Curriculum Reform, 1964 (Box 34)
  - Enrollment Data - Attrition (1956-1963) (Box 34)
  - Engineering Physics and Material Science - Curricula and Sets of Objectives (Box 34)
  - ECSC - Minutes and Statements (Box 34)
  - Studies - Undergraduate Education, 1963 (Box 34)
  - Engineering College Report, 1963 (Box 34)
  - Policy Committee, 1969 (Box 34)
  - Policy Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 34)
  - College of Engineering Faculty Memos, 1960 (Box 34)
  - Policy Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 34)
  - Policy Committee - Special Reports, Studies, Communiques, etc. (Box 34)
  - Report of the Policy Committee to the College of Engineering, 1958-1959 (Box 34)
  - Minutes - Policy Committee, 1959 (Box 34)
  - Minutes - Engineering College Faculty, 1969 (Box 34)
  - Various Engineering College Reports and Memos (Box 34)
  - Various Engineering College Reports and Memos (Box 34)
  - Various Engineering College Reports and Memos (Box 34)
  - Various Engineering College Reports and Memos (Box 34)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Education, 1964 (Box 35)
  - Engineering Design Committee, 1964 (Box 35)
  - Design Program, 1967 (Box 35)
  - Engineering Design Committee, 1967 (Box 35)
  - Education in Engineering Design, 1963 (Box 35)
  - Engineering Design Education Proposal, 1965 (Box 35)
  - Suggested References to use in Quotes (Box 35)
  - Engineering Design Committee, 1964 (Box 35)
  - Sibley Faculty (Box 35)
  - Faculty - College of Engineering, 1961 (Box 35)
  - Meeting - June 12, 1964 1964 (Box 35)
  - Faculty Lists, 1971-1973 (Box 35)
  - Faculty Lists (Box 35)
  - Faculty Data, 1972 (Box 35)
- Series XIII. Development and Corporate Relations (Box 8, 9, 13, 18)
  - Trip Reports, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Placement Reports, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Milwaukee Visits, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Standard Oil Company, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Committee - Fund Raising; 1, 1970's (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Committee - Fund Raising; 2, 1970's (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Committee - Fund Raising Report: "Report of Committee and Acquisition and Use of Gifts", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Committee - Fund Raising-Correspondence and Memos, 1078-1980 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Engineering Development-AT&T (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - "An Invitation to Become a Member of the Cornell Injection Molding Program", January 1979 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Engineering Development - St. Louis, Pittsburgh, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Engineering Development - Correspondence, 1972-March 1979 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Engineering Development - Correspondence, April-December 1979 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Engineering Development - Correspondence, January-May 1980 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Engineering Development - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Engineering Development - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Engineering Development - Correspondence, June 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Consortium on Financing Higher Education - Study of Development and University Relations, December 1976 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Industrial Liaison Program at Cornell, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - C.R. - "Universities and the Future of Computer Technology Development," "Universities and Technology Growth" by Kenneth Wilson (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Corporate Relations - Interviews with Faculty, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Corporate Liaison Committee - Schultz Appointment, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Corporate Liaison Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Report of the ad hoc Committee to Advise on Ways of Increasing Outside Research Support to the University, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Overview of Cornell's Corporate Relations Program (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Survey of Industrial - University Relations, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Summary of Corporate Gifts and Grants, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Report to the Corporate Liaison Committee - "The University-Industry Relationship in Perspective", October 1981 (Box 9)
  - Report as a Result of Survey of Industrial-University Relations, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Continuing Education - Special Programs Facility, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Corporate Relations - Faculty Council of Representatives, Research Policies: Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Corporate Research Foundation, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Corporate Relations - Outside Funding, 1978-1982 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Conference - University-Corporate Relations, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - American Institute of Industrial Engineers, 1959-1962 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Technological Innovation Be Directed?"; Thoughts on the Development of a Ph.D. Thesis Proposal" (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Berth Donald - Papers - "CAN/Should Technological Innovation Be Directed?"; Thoughts on the Development of a Ph.D. Thesis Proposal" (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - N. Y. Telephone Co. 1957 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Patent rights 1970-1988 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Western Electric Advisory Committee study (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Western Electric performance evaluation materials 1962-1966 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Western Electric background info 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Western Electric research 1959-1962 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Western Electric publicity 1960 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Western Electric engineering preliminary report 1961 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Report on Research and Western Electric engineering given by A. Schultz 1960 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Western Electric miscellaneous papers 1957-1960 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Series XIV. Slides
  - Slides (Box 10)
- Series XV. Mapcase items
  - Accounts, photo stats of graphs/charts, investment sheets, production documents and some machine plans (Folder 1)